Denaris

Docs typed by Belgarath

Loading Instructions
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

CBM Amiga

Power on your computer. When the "WORKBENCH" screen
appears, insert the PROGRAM DISK into drive DF0. The
program will load automatically. You will be prompted to
exchange disks when required.

(cracked versions are only 1 disk)


Scenario
~~~~~~~~
Throughout time, man has been a victim of his own intelligence
and his insatiable thirst for knowledge. The planet Denaris is
a horrifying example. Scientists created machines which
became so sophisticated they no longer depended on man - 
and so began a rule of tyranny. The Denarian people tried in
vain to destroy the machines, with a mighty ballistic missile,
but from the ashes of the nuclear fires, the machines rose up - 
more powerful than ever. Trapped in an underground
stronghold, now the Denarians' only hope for freedom is the
D5-H75 Eagle Fighter, an ultra refined space glider. Control the
Eagle Fighter in this epic crusade against evil, and win freedom
at last for Denaris.


CBM Amiga Version
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Upon completion of loading you will be required to choose
between either a 1 or 2 player game, do this with the joystick
in port 2.

You also have the option after playing to save your score to the 
HIGH SCORE TABLE. To do this ensure the data disk is NOT write
protected. (Disk 1 is the program disk, disk 2 is the data disk).

(Again, cracked versions are only 1 disk, and for WinUAE users
it's advisable to use save states rather than save to the disk)

To PAUSE the game press P, to continue playing press the FIRE
button.

Each player starts with 5 ships.


Extra Weapons
~~~~~~~~~~~~~
While travelling through the underground stronghold you are
able to fuse with the following objects.

 .  M SCATTER-SHOT
. . Increases the fire-power of the player. Two, four 
    or eight projectiles will be shot. This is
    dependant on the number of symbols you have 
    already collected.
    
>>  S SPEED-UP
    Increases the flying speed of the player.
    BEWARE: A fighter that is flying too quickly
    cannot be well navigated.

~   B LIGHTNING BLITZ-SHOT
    Special lazer that is reflected off of super-
    structures. It is therefore a very strong weapon.

N   G OBJECT-SEEKER
    An energy-ball that automatically attacks the
    strongest opponent.

O   K PROTECTION-SATELLITE
    Joint-energy-ball that protects the player from
    an attacking shot. After one of these symbols
    has been collected, a joint-energy-ball follows
    the player from underneath. When two have
    been collected, another follows the player from
    above.

Ф   P POWER-SHOT
    If the FIRE button is pressed for a long time
    after the collection of one of these symbols, an
    energy-beam will be shot. This is a very effective
    weapon which temporarily blocks your normal
    shooting-power. In addition these weapons
    cannot be used with the R-Ball.

O=  R R-BALL
    A Plasma-Ball that can dock onto the player's
    ship. By pressing the FIRE button the ball can
    be released. However, direct collision with an
    opponent reduces the amount of energy and as
    a result opponents shots will not be absorbed.
    The R-Ball cannot be used together with the
    Power-Shot.



© 1989 SOFTGOLD. All rights reserved. Manafactured and
distributed under license from Rainbow Arts by GO! Media
Holdings Limited, a division of U.S. Gold Limited, Units 2/3
Holford Way, Holford, Birmingham B6 7AX.

Typed by Belgarath